{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hertz","incorrectAnswers":["Joule","Watt","Pascal"],"question":"What are the units of measurement for Frequency?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"0","incorrectAnswers":["3","1","6"],"question":"How many moons does Mercury have?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Calcium carbonate","incorrectAnswers":["Deuterium Oxide","Calcium magnesium carbonate","Sodium bicarbonate"],"question":"What chemical compound makes limestone?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Athens","incorrectAnswers":["Jerusalem","Moscow","Venice"],"question":"In which city would you find the Acropolis?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Anemia","incorrectAnswers":["Diabetes","Cancer","Arthritis"],"question":"What disease may be diagnosed by checking Vitamin B12 levels and is characterized by a lack of red blood cells?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"W. K. Clifford","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Ludwig Wittgenstein","Epictetus"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'It is wrong always, everywhere and for everyone, to believe anything upon insufficient evidence'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ireland","incorrectAnswers":["Scotland","Wales","France"],"question":"Which country is associated with a harp, which is featured on its national emblem?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Three Times","incorrectAnswers":["Once","No Times","Five Times"],"question":"How many times did Peter deny Jesus?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"160","incorrectAnswers":["0","50","300"],"question":"Approximately how many children did pharaoh Ramses II father?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Diagonally","incorrectAnswers":["Vertically","Horizontally","Backwards"],"question":"The king crab walks __________","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1989","incorrectAnswers":["1980","1985","1994"],"question":"In which year did the Berlin Wall fall?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Lot","incorrectAnswers":["Boys","Witches","Game"],"question":"Stephen King's: \"Salem's _________\".","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"DNA","incorrectAnswers":["GCI","ATP","COD"],"question":"What is the abbreviation for the polymer that carries genetic instructions for living cells?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Roman Polanski","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed The Pianist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Autobahn","incorrectAnswers":["Bundestrasse","Reichstag","Schwartzkopf"],"question":"What word is used for Germany's main highways?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1967","incorrectAnswers":["1922","1869","1894"],"question":"In which year did the Six-Day War take place?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Spiced Ham ","incorrectAnswers":["Special Made Artifial Meat","Superior Manufactured Artificial Meat","Special Ham"],"question":"What Is 'SPAM' Short For?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Motörhead","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Motley Crüe"],"question":"Which band was founded by Lemmy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Not my tempo.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Today, I consider myself the luckiest man on the face of the earth.\"","\"Just keep swimming.\"","\"You shall not pass!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Whiplash'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Virgin","incorrectAnswers":["Unrefined","Pure","Organic"],"question":"What grade of olive oil comes only from mechanically pressed olives with no chemical treatment?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Crying Game","incorrectAnswers":["Sunset Boulevard","Bringing Up Baby","A Clockwork Orange"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Dil'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The art using make-up","incorrectAnswers":["Winemaking","The Sumerians","The cosmos"],"question":"What is Cosmetology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mistletoe","incorrectAnswers":["Holly","Mimosa","Lavender"],"question":"At Christmas, it is customary to exchange kisses beneath a sprig of which plant?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A sedge","incorrectAnswers":["A sloth","A yoke","An unkindness"],"question":"What is the word for a group of herons?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Yak","incorrectAnswers":["Goat","Lama","Bison"],"question":"Which Small Breed Of Cattle Is Found Wile In The Tibetan Plateu , North Of The Himalayas","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Grand prix","incorrectAnswers":["Bon appétit","Vive la France","C'est la vie"],"question":"What is the French term for a big prize?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Spinal cord","incorrectAnswers":["Vagus nerve","Ribcage","Trachea"],"question":"In the human body, what is the name of the structure that runs down the middle of the back?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Baz Luhrmann","incorrectAnswers":["Darren Aronofsky","Christopher Nolan","Steven Spielberg"],"question":"Which director of the film \"Moulin Rouge!\" brought his hit production of \"La boheme\" to Broadway in 2002?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mini","incorrectAnswers":["Beetle","Porsche 911","E-Type"],"question":"Which iconic car did Austin And Morris launch in 1959?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Million Dollar Baby","incorrectAnswers":["The Aviator","Finding Neverland","Ray"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2004?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Joey","incorrectAnswers":["Ross","Chandler","Buster"],"question":"What is the name of the character played by Matt LeBlanc on 'Friends'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The 1950s","incorrectAnswers":["The 1960s","The 1970s","The 1980s"],"question":"Which decade is known for literary works such as \"The Crucible\" and \"On the Road\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Marquis de Sade","incorrectAnswers":["Nikolai Gogol","J. R. R. Tolkien","Virginia Woolf"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The 120 Days of Sodom'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Monopoly","incorrectAnswers":["Scrabble","Chess","Risk"],"question":"Which board game can you get in a French language edition, with properties like Place du Parc and Promenade?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1927","incorrectAnswers":["1918","1936","1945"],"question":"When was the first movie with sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Zoe Saldana","incorrectAnswers":["Catherine Deneuve","Audrey Hepburn","Rachel Weisz"],"question":"Which actress has starred in films including Avengers: Endgame and Avatar?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Slipknot","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which heavy metal band from the United States released the studio album 'Iowa'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A young boy, left without attention, delves into a life of petty crime.","incorrectAnswers":["A sole survivor tells of the twisty events leading up to a horrific gun battle on a boat.","The final secretary for Adolf Hitler tells of the Nazi dictator's final days.","An aspiring musician enters the Land of the Dead to find his great-great-grandfather."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie The 400 Blows?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Lithuania","Sweden","Serbia"],"question":"Milan is a city in which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Ming","incorrectAnswers":["Tang","Qing","Wu"],"question":"Which dynasty ruled China from 1368- to 1644?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Athletics","incorrectAnswers":["Boxing","Motor racing","Rowing"],"question":"With which sport is Kenenisa Bekele associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The blue whale","incorrectAnswers":["The elephant","The giraffe","The hippopotamus"],"question":"What is the largest mammal in the world?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Share moments. Share life.","incorrectAnswers":["Your vision. Our future.","At the heart of the image","See what we mean"],"question":"What is the marketing slogan of Kodak?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Heights","incorrectAnswers":["Sir Mix-A-Lot","House of Pain","Men Without Hats"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1992 with How Do You Talk to an Angel??","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hippie","incorrectAnswers":["Grunge","Gothic","Preppy"],"question":"What is the name of the fashion trend popularized in the 1960s that involves wearing bright colors and psychedelic patterns?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A man becomes concerned for his Jewish workforce after witnessing their persecution by the Nazis.","incorrectAnswers":["In order to power the city, beasts have to scare children so that they scream.","A girl wanders into a world ruled by gods, witches, and spirits, where humans are changed into beasts.","King Arthur and his Knights embark on a search for a religious relic."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Schindler's List?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Cm","incorrectAnswers":["C","Cu","Cr"],"question":"What is the chemical symbol for curium?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Elton John","incorrectAnswers":["David Bowie","John Lennon","Tom Jones"],"question":"Who Was The Star Behind Rocket Records?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Beijing","incorrectAnswers":["Hong Kong","Shanghai","Chengdu"],"question":"What is the capital of China?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"It Takes Two","incorrectAnswers":["I Touch Myself","How Bizarre","Whip It"],"question":"What song did Rob Base & DJ E-Z Rock have a hit with in 1988?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hit and run","incorrectAnswers":["Crush and leave","Drive and go","Smack and flee"],"question":"What is the term used to describe an accident in which the driver flees the scene?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Attila the Huns","incorrectAnswers":["Vlad the Impaler","Ivan the Terrible","Xerxes"],"question":"Which ancient ruler was known as the \"Scourge of God\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Germany","incorrectAnswers":["Luxembourg","Denmark","Switzerland"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Kingdom of the Netherlands?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Spice Girls","incorrectAnswers":["Girls Aloud","All Saints","B*Witched"],"question":"Which 90's girl group was Victoria Beckham a member of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Deer Hunter","incorrectAnswers":["Coming Home","Heaven Can Wait","Midnight Express"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1978?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"US Dollar","incorrectAnswers":["Euro","Japanese Yen","British Pound"],"question":"What is the most traded currency in the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"A Pea ","incorrectAnswers":["A Squash","A mushroom","A root"],"question":"What Type Of Vegetable Is A Marrow Fat?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Laughing my ass off","incorrectAnswers":["Letting me air out","Loving my ambitious outlook","Leading me and objecting"],"question":"If someone typed the letters 'LMAO' in a message, what would they mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sodium hydroxide","incorrectAnswers":["Sodium tetraborate decahydrate","Silicon dioxide","Deuterium oxide"],"question":"What chemical has the formula NaOH?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Russia","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Thailand","Cambodia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders People's Republic of China?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Law of Conservation of Energy","incorrectAnswers":["Law of Universal Gravitation","Law of Thermodynamics","Law of the Lever"],"question":"What is the name of the physical law that states that energy is neither created or destroyed?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Color Field Painting","incorrectAnswers":["Foreshortening","Gestural Painting","Canvas Filling"],"question":"Which technique in abstract painting developed in the 1950's focuses on the effects of large areas of color having a minimum of surface detail?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Polka","incorrectAnswers":["Bolka","Molka","Tolka"],"question":"What word could refer to a dance or a dot?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Turkic","Austronesian","Dravidian"],"question":"The language 'Iranian Persian' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Mongols","incorrectAnswers":["The Huns","The Parthians","The Greeks"],"question":"Which people were led by Genghis Khan?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Émile Zola","incorrectAnswers":["Alphonse Daudet","Anatole France","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Thérèse Raquin'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Jawaharlal Nehru","incorrectAnswers":["Mahatma Gandhi","Indira Gandhi","Subhas Chandra Bose"],"question":"Who was the first Prime Minister of India?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Atlanta Falcons","incorrectAnswers":["Atlanta Dynamo","Atlanta Marlins","Atlanta Rockets"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in Atlanta?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Lady Gaga","incorrectAnswers":["Hikaru Utada","Drake","Madonna"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter, and actress released the song 'G.U.Y.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"E. B. White","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Jordan","Philip K. Dick","Isabel Allende"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Charlotte's Web'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Joe Dimaggio","incorrectAnswers":["Jesse Jackson","Michael Jordan","Mohammed Ali"],"question":"Which sportsman is mentioned in the Simon & Garfunkel song Mrs Robinson?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Confirmed the theory that Earth revolves around The Sun.","incorrectAnswers":["Roman ruler who overthrew Caesar Augustus","Physicist who made major discoveries in quantum theory.","38th President of the US."],"question":"Which of the following describes Galileo Galilei?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tej","incorrectAnswers":["Horilka","Canelazo","Sangria"],"question":"Which of these is a popular drink in Ethiopia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bob Dylan","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Young","Eric Clapton","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American musician released the song 'Mr. Tambourine Man'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn","incorrectAnswers":["Henryk Sienkiewicz","Oscar Wilde","Ivan Turgenev"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Gulag Archipelago'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Simon & Garfunkel","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American music duo released the song 'Mrs. Robinson'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Doe","incorrectAnswers":["A Leopardess","A Vixen","A Ewe"],"question":"What is a female mouse known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sean Connery","incorrectAnswers":["George Lazenby","Roger Moore","Pierce Brosnan"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in Goldfinger?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Werner Heisenberg","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen Hawking","Gregor Mendel","Leonhard Euler"],"question":"Which influential theoretical physicist was one of the pioneers of Quantum mechanics?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ankylosaurus","incorrectAnswers":["Triceratops","Stegosaurus","Parasaurolophus"],"question":"What is the name of the dinosaur with a club-like tail?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Crayfish","incorrectAnswers":["Earth materials","Blood","The night sky"],"question":"What is Astacology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Eagles","incorrectAnswers":["Led Zeppelin","Black Sabbath","Aerosmith"],"question":"'Witchy Woman' was a hit for which rock group in the 1970's?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"I don't care","incorrectAnswers":["Interdependent carers","In da crew","I'm doing crap"],"question":"If someone typed the letters 'IDC' in a message, what would they mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Laika the Dog","incorrectAnswers":["Churley the Chimpanzee","Feefo the Cat","Monty the Rat"],"question":"Who Was The First Animal In Space?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Beetles","incorrectAnswers":["The Shroud of Turin","Angels","The upper atmosphere"],"question":"What is Coleopterology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Roll","incorrectAnswers":["Dough","Pull","Wrap"],"question":"Who is Mega Man's sister?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Central Intelligence Agency","incorrectAnswers":["Federal Bureau of Investigation","Internal Revenue Service","National Aeronautics and Space Administration"],"question":"What is the name of the United States government organization established in 1947 with headquarters in Langley, Virginia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Swipe right","incorrectAnswers":["Like it","Thumbs up","Heart it"],"question":"What is the two-word term that the Tinder app has popularized, meaning to accept or approve of something?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Othello","incorrectAnswers":["Romeo","Juliet","Mercutio"],"question":"Which of the following characters is not a part of Shakespeare's 'Romeo and Juliet'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"It is used in fertilizers, rocket propellants and fireworks.","incorrectAnswers":["It is used in baking to stabilize egg whites.","It is used as an ingredient in the production of glass, bricks, and ceramics.","It is a poisonous gas."],"question":"What is the chemical potassium nitrate often used for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Madrid","incorrectAnswers":["San Marino","Barcelona","Seville"],"question":"What is the capital city of Spain?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. R. R. Tolkien","incorrectAnswers":["G. K. Chesterton","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Hobbit'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Crete ","incorrectAnswers":["Corfu","Mykonos","Rhodes"],"question":"Which Is The Largest Of The Greek Islands?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'I Feel Fine'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Basketball","incorrectAnswers":["Track and field","Motor racing","Boxing"],"question":"With which sport is Magic Johnson associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Humpty Dumpty","incorrectAnswers":["Hey Diddle Diddle","Mary Had a Little Lamb","Baa Baa Black Sheep"],"question":"What nursery rhyme is about a man who falls off a wall?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ben Kingsley","incorrectAnswers":["Kiefer Sutherland","Michael Douglas","Josh Brolin"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Iron Man 3 and Schindler's List?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Thailand","incorrectAnswers":["China","Saudi Arabia","Turkey"],"question":"What country was formerly known as Siam?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"feces","incorrectAnswers":["underground water","the field of medicine that deals with the skin","drug dosage"],"question":"What is Scatology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},